<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Classically Trained]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[A Musician's guide to music and fitness]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://classically-trained.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-21T23:41:12.418Z</updated>
  <id>http://classically-trained.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Classically Trained]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[press@ctrained.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Going Vegan Part 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-3/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-3/</id>
    <published>2014-02-17T03:56:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:13.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of unhealthy vegan foods out there.  You can be totally meat, dairy, and cholesterol free and eat food that has next to no nutrients.  Usually these foods come in the form of baked goods, imitation meats and cheeses, and fried concoctions...<a id="more"></a>not to mention all the processed food that is accidentally vegan, like Oreos, potato chips, and soft drinks.  So here are some ways to go from junk to joy.</p>
<h3 id="buy-most-of-your-groceries-in-the-produce-section">BUY MOST OF YOUR GROCERIES IN THE PRODUCE SECTION</h3>
<p>You can eat 3 meals a day, have dessert, snacks, and make delicious drinks all without ever having to buy food that comes in a package.  Find the grocery store that has the biggest produce section and do all your shopping there.  The more aisles the store has, the less room they are making for real food.  If you have the option (and this is even BETTER) to shop at a farmer’s market, then absolutely do your shopping there.  You’ll find food that is fresh, seasonal, locally grown, and often organic.  This is the ideal way to eat for health, and the funnest way to cook!</p>
<h3 id="if-you-must-buy-boxed-foods-read-the-ingredients">IF YOU MUST BUY BOXED FOODS, READ THE INGREDIENTS</h3>
<p>Check that label.  Don’t just read the serving size, the number of calories, sodium content, and nutrients.  Read the actual ingredients.  They are listed in the order of content.  So the first word is what that item has the most of.  If the first word is “sugar,” or code for sugar, i.e.: something ending in “-ose” or “syrup,” then you’re most likely looking at a product that isn’t good for you.  Another common first ingredient is flour.  Now, I’m not gluten-free, but I do avoid eating processed foods that are made with simple flours.  They are almost always junk, and devoid of actual nutrition.  So I skip it.  If the product has more than 5 ingredients, I skip it.  And finally, if it has ingredients I can’t pronounce, I definitely put it back.  Chemicals, preservatives, sugars, and animal products have deceptively long scientific names.  </p>
<h3 id="don-t-be-fooled-by-healthy-labeling">DON’T BE FOOLED BY HEALTHY LABELING</h3>
<p>Many manufacturers attempt to draw a healthy crowd to their processed food by putting things like “whole grain” and “low cholesterol” and “low carb” on their labels.  Don’t be fooled.  Always judge a product by its ingredient list, not its advertisement.  As an extension, soft drinks labeled as “diet” are simply sweetened with aspartame, an artificial sweetener that is 4 times as potent as sugar, and therefore is very low in calories.  The problem is, diet drinks are addictive and often lead to an increase in appetite.  The sweetness is just enough to give your brain that little hint, but it will keep bugging you for more.  It’s better to drink a beverage that has nutrients in it, so it fills you up and satisfies you.  When possible, home-made is best.  You can make your own orange juice, lemonade, tea, almond milk...there are endless options, and you get to control the content, and save money.</p>
<h3 id="replacing-your-favorite-foods">REPLACING YOUR FAVORITE FOODS</h3>
<p>This is one of the hardest things to do when making the switch.  If you’re used to eating burgers for lunch on Tuesday and pizza on the weekends, you may find yourself whimpering to the fridge and then slamming it shut in resentment at the sight of your bell peppers waiting to be stuffed.  Take heart.  There is such a thing as vegan burgers, pizza, mac and cheese, and more.  And lots of times they are better than the original!  With a little simple research you can find alternative ways to make pretty much any comfort food in existence.  At first, these may be the training wheels you need if you’re not ready to branch out into the vast unknown of original, plant based cuisine.  Try making veggie burgers out of quinoa, beans, nuts and seeds, lentils...there are dozens of options.  You can try vegan “meats” made of seitan, (which is a lot like sausage) tofu, and tempeh.  These are not only excellent sources of protein, but they provide a more rich experience similar to the carnivorous one.  As you get more comfortable with fruits and veggies as the base of your diet, then your palate will begin to crave much more variety, and that’s where the fun begins! </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of unhealthy vegan foods out there.  You can be totally meat, dairy, and cholesterol free and eat food that has next to no nutrients.  Usually these foods come in the form of baked goods, imitation meats and cheeses, and fried concoctions...]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Going Vegan" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/series/Going%20Vegan/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Prepare for the future by focusing on the present]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/prepare-for-the-future-by-focusing-on-the-present/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/prepare-for-the-future-by-focusing-on-the-present/</id>
    <published>2014-02-11T03:10:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:42.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Being performers, we live and thrive in a world where what we put forth is at the mercy of how it’s perceived by an audience.  Your wig, your stage makeup, your costume, the lighting, it all creates an illusion that is tailored for the public.  <a id="more"></a>Nothing in the realm of a staged presentation is actually intimate in the traditional sense.</p>
<p>I sang a very important audition last week, for a one man audience, in a choral rehearsal space, in the standard manner.  I dressed my best (but not in a black dress because well, that’s boring) choosing instead a bright white and gray outfit with silver accessories.  Now, I have been singing consistently in fully staged productions for several years, and have sung fewer and fewer auditions; zero, in fact, in the past 2 years.  While to the outside ear this seems to be an indication of success, as the time came closer to my big day, I was getting more and more fearful.  What if I forgot the words to my big arias?  What if the parts that were easy before had become inaccessible now?  I had my old list of 5 or 6 go-tos, all varying in language and style.  But these were incredibly difficult pieces that I couldn’t just roll out of bed and sing on any given day.  So I of course spent a lot of time practicing and preparing, getting these pieces back into my voice.  And yes, your voice today is not the voice you had last year.  So I made some adjustments, and assessed where my voice felt in the present.</p>
<p>The present.  Now, there’s an idea.  Yes, some things felt weird, but others felt incredibly free...I have no idea what exactly I’d been doing differently other than growing and shifting as any human does, and all I could think as audition day approached was, “well, sing with what you have.  Pretend you’re on stage and you’re the star of the show.”  </p>
<p>I arrived a half hour early and tried to get myself to just breathe.  I hadn’t felt that nervous in a long time.  The presenter showed up ten minutes early and wanted me to begin immediately, but my manager had not yet arrived.  I was already nervous when he asked me why I needed to wait for my manager; he wasn’t going to sing!  Eventually everyone showed up but I was a bundle of insecurity before it was my turn on the stage.  </p>
<p>As the door closed behind me, I presented my best professional manner, which to me means:</p>
<ol>
<li>Smile and greet the person with confidence</li>
<li>Take the stage as yourself; you don’t need to impress anybody but you know you are fabulous</li>
<li>Announce what piece you will sing concisely; wait for the pianist to get himself situated</li>
<li>Gracefully present your face in character before the start of the intro</li>
</ol>
<p>Then it all boiled down to one final thing.  The best presentation of my best intentions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We judge others by their actions; we judge ourselves by our intentions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the weeks leading up to this 10 minute window of time, I’d gone through every possible scenario in my head.  At night I pictured myself forgetting words, missing entrances, skipping phrases by accident, getting lost.  I realized that these nightmares were not going to help me and certainly weren’t going to win the day.  If you give these presentiments (fears) power, they grow pretty incessantly and take over your life!  Stage fright manifests itself way before you ever hit the stage and open your mouth.  </p>
<p>As I felt these negative thoughts creeping in, I actively combated them with positive thoughts AND actions.  After all, the idea that you’ll do well is not enough.  Just like the visualization of success, while powerful, is not sufficient to guarantee a winning situation.  It must be combined with the practice of getting there, the literal, grinding work.  And because others judge you by your actions (that 10 minute slot you have to impress a casting director) that is all you have left to rely on.  Therefore, allow your intentions to motivate your actions.  You want to sing your absolute best?  You know what has to be lined up in order for that to happen.  You want to look great?  You know how long it takes you to get ready and make sure everything is in place.  You want to be on time?  You know what time to leave your house.</p>
<p>Letting your intentions (that is, the desire to succeed) guide your actions in all the time leading up to a presentation is incredibly important, and it doesn’t stop once you are on that stage.  That is the time when intentions morph into musical manifestations.  Every inhale is an intention to sing a phrase.  Every crescendo is a building block to a special moment, or a dramatic beat.  Every note has a purpose, a reason for being there.  Before you begin to sing, know what your character has just experienced, and what they want to express, and WHY they must express it.  If there is an idea behind every word you sing, it will show very clearly to an audience of one person, or 1,000 people.  </p>
<p>The same goes for how you hold your body when you sing.  People ask a lot, “is it okay to move during an audition?  Should I just stand still?  Do I grab the piano?”  The answers to these questions lie in your own mind.  How do YOU feel when you watch someone else sing a recital or a solo concert or even a solo scene on stage, and they grab the piano?  How do you react to their connection to their own body?  Do you tense up?  Do you feel nervous or afraid for them?  Chances are, you are reflecting what they are putting out, and it’s your job as a singer then, to make sure what you put out to an audience is what you intend.  </p>
<p>As I sang my arias, I felt myself naturally wanting to do specific things, and I just went with it.  Why fight it?  These are characters I’ve played on stage, and I felt confident that if I moved with purpose or even stood still with purpose, it would read equally as well in this small room.  What I kept telling myself was “Commit.  If you’re going to move your arm, move your arm, finish the action, fulfill the intention, and then put your arm down.”  That is something I learned from a wonderful director, Stephen Wadsworth at the Met.  Acting (and singing) is about making a commitment, a decision to go with something 100% and seeing it through.  That shows confidence.  It’s a musical phrase, it’s a dramatic phrase.  </p>
<p>When I finished, I realized that I had sung one of the best auditions of my life, because I focused on my intentions both musically and dramatically, and they put me at ease and made me sing better.  For the first time in any of my auditions, I finally felt like a professional.  </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Being performers, we live and thrive in a world where what we put forth is at the mercy of how it’s perceived by an audience.  Your wig, your stage makeup, your costume, the lighting, it all creates an illusion that is tailored for the public.  ]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Lessons Learned" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Lessons%20Learned/"/>
    
      <category term="Auditioning" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Auditioning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Going vegan part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-2/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-2/</id>
    <published>2014-02-04T02:58:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:36.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things you will encounter most often is questions from curious or critical friends about your new lifestyle.  You may even question yourself sometimes...<a id="more"></a>Where do you get your protein?  What about vitamin B-12?  How can you possibly live without cheese?  These are probing and valid questions, and you’ll hear them a lot.  The worst thing is to get a critical turn to these questions, and that’s where learning to stand up for yourself is important.  Here are some tips to deal with nosy nay-sayers.</p>
<h3 id="do-your-research">Do your Research</h3>
<p>If you don’t want to have a debate about going plant based, that’s fine, but you might want to have a few simple questions answered for the common man’s curiosity.  Where DO you get your protein?  What’s the difference between vegan and gluten-free?  Do you still eat eggs?  Be clear on where you stand so that you can smile and present your case.  If and when (and believe me this will happen) you get an argumentative nutritionist, you can invite them to a more detailed conversation later.  The point is, you don’t want to come across as judgemental or self-righteous, even though no matter what you do, your salad at the lunch table might make people feel bad.  And that’s not your problem!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you eat seasonally, organically, and (ideally all of these) locally, you are always getting the freshest food on your plate</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="be-a-beacon">Be a beacon</h3>
<p>There are lots of veggies out there, and there are more every day.  It’s okay to share recipes, post pictures, and share in your green delight.  Don’t be ashamed of it.  For every person who hates the idea of tofu, there are 5 people who love the idea!  So spread the light!  Ask your more experienced veggie friends for new ideas to try.  There are tons of tricks out there that are just a message or a click away!  And same goes for you:  While you don’t need to go around making people sniff your plate, DO open the door (and share the recipes) to people who you might inspire.</p>
<h3 id="make-sure-you-re-getting-a-balanced-diet">Make sure you&#39;re getting a balanced diet</h3>
<p>As with any diet, it’s very easy to settle back into a few staples and stay there.  The best thing about being a veggie is that you have constant variety, if you allow yourself to be open to it.  If you eat seasonally, organically, and (ideally all of these) locally, you are always getting the freshest food on your plate.  However, without variety, you could be missing out on important nutrients that you need to function optimally.  And this means more than protein!  Again, do your research and learn the best plant sources of things like iron, calcium, vitamin C (kiwi!) potassium, just to name a few…you’d be surprised how some of your favorite plants (nuts, seeds for example) can come up major winners!  One of my absolute rules when putting together a meal is to make sure to get as many colors on my plate as possible.  Nature is wonderful at giving itself away at first sight.  A rainbow plate is well rounded and extremely nutritious!</p>
<h3 id="find-support">Find Support</h3>
<p>There are numerous blogs, forums, websites, groups you can join to find inspiration.  While many vegans choose the plant based lifestyle for environmental or ethical reasons, there are serious health benefits to eating this way.  Find out what speaks to you.  You may find that being an ethical vegan resonates more than being a person who simply wants to live a healthier lifestyle and lower their cholesterol.  No matter what your motivation, there are many people who feel the same way, and knowing you’re not alone helps this journey feel more like a lifestyle and not a diet.  We are not weight-watchers.  We are here for each other as fellow beings who want to be exemplary in health.  </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things you will encounter most often is questions from curious or critical friends about your new lifestyle.  You may even question yourself sometimes...]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Going Vegan" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/series/Going%20Vegan/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Cleanse]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/the-cleanse/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/the-cleanse/</id>
    <published>2014-01-29T23:02:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:46.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had an emotional day today. Blame it on a gorgeous but sad opera, an overwhelming sense of beauty that I&#39;m constantly surrounded by, and a vulnerability that allows me to be open to it. Being open is scary. It puts you at emotional risk. <a id="more"></a>Any little thing that would normally bounce off of you as a joke will suddenly feel like a stab in the heart. Something happened, and I was feeling really sensitive but I held it back at work. Then I came home where it was safe, and just bawled. Steven comforted me and we went for a run together. I cried and then sweated out a very deeply felt 5 miles. I turned to my body to cleanse my spirit, and I feel like a true human being. Cleansed by tears and sweat; would you call that baptism?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Being open is scary. It puts you at emotional risk.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The cleansing power of water, the great “element” that we are almost completely made of; it has power to refresh and bring life.  This cleansing came from within; it wasn’t that I went and dunked myself in a pool.  This was water that streamed from inside my flesh, with the power of my emotions, and the gift and mystery that is my body.  </p>
<p>Christ’s words “The Kingdom of God is neither here nor there; it is within you,” mean so much more to me when I have experiences like this.  I am so thankful for the gift of being alive on this earth, a being that was created for a purpose.  Love, light, spreading the idea that what we have inside are seeds for a garden that bears the fruit of absolute joy.  Happiness comes from within, it is cultivated within, and it pours out through you.  Is that why we call those tiny holes “pores?”  God I love English.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had an emotional day today. Blame it on a gorgeous but sad opera, an overwhelming sense of beauty that I&#39;m constantly surrounded by, and a vulnerability that allows me to be open to it. Being open is scary. It puts you at emotional risk. ]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Exercise" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Exercise/"/>
    
      <category term="Emotions" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Emotions/"/>
    
      <category term="The Great Element" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/The%20Great%20Element/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Going Vegan Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-1/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-part-1/</id>
    <published>2014-01-29T03:56:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today someone told me they were thinking of going vegetarian and wanted some advice.  Naturally my first response was “learn to cook.”  She asked if I used cookbooks or just invented things off the top of my head.  Now, I’ve been vegan for 4 years and I cook all my meals, but 75% of the time I follow directions from a book.  <a id="more"></a>I’m one of those personalities that doesn’t want to play the invention/experimentation game when there’s a stomach to feed.  Plus I like to try new things!  Cooking takes practice, but it also takes a sense of acceptance.  You have to accept that it takes time, patience, and frankly, a reliable set of ingredients.  Here are some tips to help you ease your way as you introduce new foods into your diet.</p>
<h3 id="try-a-new-vegetable-each-week-">TRY A NEW VEGETABLE EACH WEEK.</h3>
<p>It’s really important to keep an open mind when you’re veering away from your standard diet.  Know that no matter how much you think you eat, there are probably dozens of fruits and veggies you’ve never bought and used.  Every week, pick something you’ve never tried (opt for something that looks fresh) at the store, take it home, and google it.  No doubt you will find hundreds of simple ways to enjoy it.</p>
<h3 id="keep-a-few-basics-on-hand-">KEEP A FEW BASICS ON HAND.</h3>
<p>For me, most of my meals start with a sautee of onion, garlic, carrots, and bell pepper.  Even if you think you don’t like them individually, together they are a wonderful foundation of flavor for any dish that isn’t a dessert or a sweet treat of some kind.  </p>
<h3 id="experiment-with-spices">EXPERIMENT WITH SPICES</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>Spices in certain combinations give wonderful warmth to dishes, and make your food feel exotic!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is so much more to life and cuisine than simple salt and pepper.  Ginger, cumin, coriander, cayenne, turmeric...I could go on forever!  Spices in certain combinations give wonderful warmth to dishes, and make your food feel exotic!  Learn what combinations go with each nationality.  For example, Mexican flavors tend towards chiles, cumin, lime, and cilantro (coriander.)  There are tons of combinations, and using your nose as your guide is downright fun!</p>
<h3 id="focus-on-what-you-can-eat-rather-than-what-you-are-missing">FOCUS ON WHAT YOU CAN EAT, RATHER THAN WHAT YOU ARE MISSING</h3>
<p>Almost every omnivore mentions how much they would miss cheese or steak, and how hard it must be to live without it.  Truth be told, those cravings can be met with much healthier ingredients and I never even think about them!  What’s important is focus.  If I focus on the delicious butternut squash I’m roasting in the oven, how the smell fills the house, I don’t have any interest in loin of pork.  When I enjoy the flavor of fresh coffee for its actual taste, and not the sweetened concoction I’ve just purchased at Starbucks, I can enjoy the subtleties much more, and I don’t need to drink as much to get the effect.  Sure, you can buy vegan versions of sausage or cheese, but face it, they will never taste exactly the same as the real thing, and why make yourself feel deprived unnecessarily?  Enjoy a rich eggplant dish or a creamy coconut milk curry.  Your palate will be bombarded with incredible flavors and you’ll save money and calories.  </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today someone told me they were thinking of going vegetarian and wanted some advice.  Naturally my first response was “learn to cook.”  She asked if I used cookbooks or just invented things off the top of my head.  Now, I’ve been vegan for 4 years and I cook all my meals, but 75% of the time I follow directions from a book.  ]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Going Vegan" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/series/Going%20Vegan/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Going Vegan: An Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-introduction/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/going-vegan-introduction/</id>
    <published>2014-01-27T03:56:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:30.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the things I get asked most often about in my daily life as an opera singer.  How does one maintain a healthy diet in our world of basic insanity?  <a id="more"></a>My journey to this lifestyle didn’t happen overnight, and it wasn’t without its challenges.  In this series, I will focus on many different aspects of eating a plant based diet.  Each post will have a variety of ideas, all of which are linked to the same goal: the journey towards a healthier diet.</p>
<p>While many people associate vegans with activism, animal rights, and environmental protection, I will do my best to focus less on those aspects and more on the health benefits.  While the sad idea of a slaughterhouse is a huge motivator for many people to turn to a cruelty-free plate, it is not the reason I originally went vegan.  That being said, YES, a vegan lifestyle benefits many beings outside of my own body; after doing some research and learning about the horrors of factory farming, for example, it made the choice to eat this way stick with me.  Knowing that you can vote with your dollar is very empowering, and you feel like a part of something greater.  You can research the benefits of going vegan by watching documentaries such as “Food, Inc,” “Fat, Sick, and Nearly Dead,” and “Vegucated.”  And of course, there’s always google.</p>
<p>As the series unfolds, I’ll go through some frequently asked questions, bust a few myths, and share some of my favorite recipes.  There is so much wonderful food out there, and we are lucky to live in a country and time period where we have access to it.  I’ll include ideas for how to eat best on the road, how to plan ahead, and how to get the most out of this incredible way of eating. </p>
<p>So here we go!  Green light please...</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the things I get asked most often about in my daily life as an opera singer.  How does one maintain a healthy diet in our world of basic insanity?  ]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Going Vegan" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/series/Going%20Vegan/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[First day of School]]></title>
    <link href="http://classically-trained.com/blog/first-day-of-school/"/>
    <id>http://classically-trained.com/blog/first-day-of-school/</id>
    <published>2014-01-20T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-21T23:40:25.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every time I begin rehearsals for a new opera, I feel like it’s the first day of school.  I pack my lunch, pick out my first outfit, decide what makeup I’m going to wear...everything has to be in presentable order.  Why?  <a id="more"></a>First impressions are important and you only get one chance at them.  Here’s what I try to always bring to the table on day #1 of any engagement:</p>
<h3 id="work-ethic">Work Ethic</h3>
<p>A fully prepared presentation complete with all the right words and notes is a must.  That way there is somewhere to go with the role.  You can’t start a race from anywhere other than the official starting line.  In other words, the training already must be complete.  And it is exactly what I want people to expect as a standard from me.  If I come in only half-memorized and not totally committed to what my character is after, that weak preparation will come around to bite me in the ass!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>First impressions are important and you only get one chance at them.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="a-nice-but-comfortable-outfit">A Nice But Comfortable Outfit</h3>
<p>Nothing says respect for your job more clearly than your wardrobe.  It reflects who you are inside.  If the first day is staging rehearsals, I wear something I can move around in, but never lounging-around-the-house wear.  And of course, over-dressing comes across as stiff and trying too hard.  Save the fancier outfits for the sitzprobe.  </p>
<h3 id="a-positive-attitude">A Positive Attitude</h3>
<p>I’m meeting most of these people for the first time, and it’s important to present my ideal self.  I am happy to be there, and excited about the upcoming project.  If I come in with reservations, ready to argue, irritable, or distressed (or worse, UNPREPARED) I’m putting forth a very negative image that will take forever to get out of people’s heads.  Clear mind, positive thoughts!</p>
<h3 id="bonus-prep-">Bonus prep:</h3>
<p>Pack your lunch
Get  your workout done before you head to work!  </p>
<p>Be fierce.
Lisette</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every time I begin rehearsals for a new opera, I feel like it’s the first day of school.  I pack my lunch, pick out my first outfit, decide what makeup I’m going to wear...everything has to be in presentable order.  Why?  ]]></summary>
    
      <category term="Practice" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Practice/"/>
    
      <category term="Preparation" scheme="http://classically-trained.com/tags/Preparation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
